Guide to the Phi Sigma Society, Lambda Chapter (The University of Montana) Records 1921-1966
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Phi Sigma Society, Lambda Chapter (The University of Montana) Records
1921-1966
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana—Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 594
Phi Sigma Society, Lambda Chapter (The University of Montana)
2.75 linear feet
The collection contains the records of the Phi Sigma Society, Lambda Chapter of The University of Montana, from its inception until the mid-1960s, probably when the society became inactive.
Historical Note
The Phi Sigma Society is an honorary society in the Biological Sciences, including the studies of Zoology, Botany, Microbiology, Geology, Bacteriology, Anthropology, and many other fields. The University of Montana’s Lambda Chapter was chartered in 1921, due to the efforts of Professor Morton J. Elrod, first chair of the science department. Other charter members included Dr. Jessie M. Bierman, the noted pediatrician, and Dr. Joseph E. Kirwood, an early University of Montana professor.
The Phi Sigma Society, Lambda Chapter (University of Montana) probably became inactive in the mid-1960s.
The collection contains the records of the Phi Sigma Society, Lambda Chapter of the University of Montana, from its inception until the mid-1960s, probably when the society became inactive. Included are records of membership, meeting minutes, finances, and publications from the national organization of the Phi Sigma Society. Part of the collection contains petitions for charters that were received from colleges and universities across the country.
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana-Missoula. Materials in Box 5 contain student grade information and are restricted.
Gift of Professor John Tibbs (Zoology), 1976.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
University of Montana-Missoula--Societies, etc.; Phi Sigma Society
Biology--Montana -- Missoula--Societies, etc.; Greek letter societies -- Montana--Missoula
Montana; Colleges and Universities; Student Life
- Faculty and student membership, notebook, 1921-1927 (Box-folder 1/1)
- Minutes, 1921-1929 (Box-folder 1/2)
- Minutes, 1929-1935 (Box-folder 1/3)
- Membership, minutes, correspondence, 1934-1963 (Box-folder 1/4)
- Phi Sigma Society, Lambda Chapter (University of Montana), writings and miscellaneous, 1941-1964 (Box-folder 1/5)
- Certificates, 1942-1953 (Box-folder 1/6)
- Receipts, 1932-1964 (Box-folder 1/7)
- Financial statements, 1932-1963 (Box-folder 1/8)
- Phi Sigma Society Constitution and By-Laws, 1959 (Box-folder 1/9)
- Miscellaneous, 1963 (Box-folder 1/10)
- General correspondence, 1930-1964 (Box-folder 2/1)
- Phi Sigma Society National Council Bulletins, 1928-1963 (Box-folder 2/2)
- Phi Sigma, Proceedings of General Meeting, 1937-1954 (Box-folder 2/3)
- Phi Sigma, University petitions for charters, 1929-1930 and undated (Box-folder 2/4)
- Phi Sigma, University petitions for charters, 1930-1938 (Box-folder 2/5)
- Phi Sigma Society, University petitions for charters, 1941-1964 (Box-folder 2/6)
- Phi Sigma Society, University petitions for charters, undated (Box-folder 2/7)
- Biology Songs, 1945 and undated (Box-folder 3/1)
- The Biologist, 1954-1963 (Box-folder 3/2)
- Phi Sigma Society, Lambda Chapter (University of Montana) member cards, A-Z, 1927-1962 (Box 4)
- Rubber stamp with Phi Sigma Society symbol, undated (Box 4)
- Phi Sigma Society, Lambda Chapter Membership Record, 1926-1966; Restricted due to member grade information (Box 5)
- College of William and Mary, Biology Club Petition for Charter, undated (Box 5)